SULAIMAN ALI

Phone: (+62) 87738114005 Mail: sulaimanali281@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sulaiman-ali-318a2a13b

Jalan Jl. Cikoko Barat 1 No.23 DKI Jakarta, 12770

PROFIL SUMMARY

Technology passionate person who spends his time involved in technology-based projects such as robotics, big data, and data analytics. A person with optimism, hardworking, ability to analyse problems, strong thinking capability, and good communication. On the other hand, he has a good team working and is easy to learn high curiosity about something new. Strong experiences in problem-solving and leadership.

EDUCATION

Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology (ITS) – Surabaya, Indonesia	2019 - 2021
S1 Bachelor's degree Engineering Physics / GPA 3,35	
Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology (ITS) – Surabaya, Indonesia	2016 - 2019
D3 Associate's degree Electrical Engineering / GPA 3,41	
7	

SKILL AND EXPERIENCE

Professional Experience

 PT. Sigma Cipta Caraka (Telkomsigma) at DIT - EPD - DSSEIS PT. Telkom Indonesia Jul 2022 -Present

Data Warehouse, Data Engineer that has responsibility for data processing end-to-end use case with DBeaver Tool, ETL data with Pentaho Tool, data-driven to decision maker, data visualization and present data findings in dashboards with Tableau Tool.

• Pertamina Integrated Enterprise Data and Command Center Dec 2021- Jun 2022

Responsible for data-driven to decision maker, data cleaning, data visualization, data analysis, interpreting, and communicating data analytics findings. Visualize and present data findings in dashboards with Power BI Tool

- Tris Dashboard Project, this dashboard used to monitoring "Risiko Gangguan Keamanan pada Proses Bisnis Pertamina"
- Satuan Tugas Ramadhan Indul Fitri 2022 Dashboard Project, this dashboard has goal to monitoring movement Indonesian society base on consumption energy.

Certificate & License

Google Data Analytics June 2022

Completed 3-month Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate. Demonstrated hands-on experience with data driven to decision maker, data cleaning, data visualization, data analysis with R, interpreting and communicating data analytics findings. Confidence in transforming complex data into actionable and clear insights. Fluency in computer programming languages and a solid understanding of database.

• Profesional Academy Digitalent Scholarship June 2022

Completed 1 month Data Scientist program with DQLAB. Practice hands-on R fundamental, SQL fundamental, statistic with R, data visualization with R, and some project related entry-level of data science.

My Research Final Project Study

• IoT Project Mobile PV

Developed and research mobile photovoltaic using fuzzy controller to be tracking the sun on two axis motor and build monitoring of it system based on Internet of Things. Mobile PV is solar tracker system with base moving. So, this project will be applied at object that can be mobile such as electric vehicle.

Remotely Operated Vehicles Underwater

Designing robot underwater vehicle that can be remoted for observation water environment

Internship

• PT Jasa Marga IoT Lab Agust 2020 - Sept 2020

In this internship, I learn Single-Lane Free Flow (SLFF) which is one of the projects undertaken by Jasa Marga IoT Lab. SLFF is an electronic transaction system, by using this payment method it hoped that road users don't need to stop their vehicles at toll gates.

• Techer of Robotic Extracurricular at Sekolah Robot Indonesia Agust 2019 - March 2020

Here I am a robotics extracurricular teacher. teach several schools in Surabaya.

• PT Cinovasi Rikaprima September 2018 - January 2019
In this internship, I learn a lot of things about internet of things. One of the projects is recognize plat number.

Tools & Application

- Business Intelligence Tools Power BI, Tableau, ETL, DBeaver, Excel, SharePoint
- Mechanical, Design 3D Inventor, Fusion
- Electronic, Design PCB, System Embedded, Microcontroller, STM32, Arduino, Proteus Simulation
- Design and editing, Sony Vegas, Corel Draw

Programing Languages:

• C/C++, Python, Html, R

Research Interest:

• Data Analyst, Data Science, Artificial Intelligence, Robotics, Internet of Things, Mechatronics, Automotive Electrical System, Automation,

ACTIVITY AND SOCIETIES

ITS ABU Robocon Robotics Team - Surabaya, Indonesia

2019-2020

Potition, Programming & Electronics Co-Lead, Researching and responsible for 'rugby robot' electronics-programming development

ICHIRO Humanoid Robot Soccer Research Team of ITS - Surabaya, Indonesia

2018-2019

Potition, Team Leader, Responsible to lead, monitor, and supervise the team for contributing to the growth of the organization. In this tim we join two international competition Robocup and FIRA HuroCup. RoboCup is an international scientific initiative with the goal to advance the state of the art of intelligent robots and the goal of the HuroCup league is to develop robots that can perform several tasks in complex environments.

ICHIRO Humanoid Robot Soccer Research Team of ITS-Surabaya, Indonesia

2017-2019

Potition, Electrical & Mechanical Division, Researching, designed, maintained and responsible for 'humanoid robot soccer' electronics-mechanical development.

ACHIEVEMENT AND AWARDS

2020

- 1st place of LAI2-COVID19 Sub Robot, Ditmawa ITS
 Designed hospital robot to respond to pandemic through technology innovation: Mobile Robot Covid-19 HOSIRO-USIRO (Hospital System Robot - Universal System Robot)
- Adhiwiramukti ITS 2020
 This award is given to me as ITS students who excel non-academic fields at 60th Dies Natalis ITS Lustrum XII
- 1st place and best strategy of Kontes Robot ABU Indonesia 2020
 Responsible to programing and operator of robot rugby as the theme of competition.
- Praktis dan Aman Kontes Robot Tematik Indonesia 2020
 Designed hospital robot that can lift patient form bad to another bad. This is to respond to pandemic through technology innovation

- 1st place of Robocup International 2019, Technical Challenge Humanoid Teen Size, Sydney, Australia
- 3rd place of Robocup International 2019, Humanoid Robot Soccer Teen size, Sydney, Australia
- 3rd place of Robocup International 2019, Technical Challenge Humanoid Kid Size, Sydney, Australia

2018

- Appreciation from Indonesia's Ministry of Youth and Sports as "Pemuda Hebat"
- 1st place of Robocup International 2018, Humanoid Robot Soccer Teen size, Montreal, Canada
- 2nd place of Robocup International 2018, Drop in Challenge Humanoid Teen size, Montreal, Canada
- 2nd place of Robocup International 2018, Technical Challenge Humanoid Teen Size, Montreal, Canada
- 3rd place of Robocup International 2018, Best Humanoid Robot, Montreal, Canada

2019

- 1_{st} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2018, Sprint Humanoid Kid Size Robot, Taichung, Taiwan
- 1_{st} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2018, United Soccer Humanoid Kid Size Robot, Taichung, Taiwan
- 2_{nd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2018, Obstacle Run Humanoid Kid Size Robot, Taichung, Taiwan
- 2_{nd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2018, Mini DRC Humanoid Kid Size Robot, Taichung, Taiwan
- 3_{rd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2018, All Round Humanoid Kid Size Robot, Taichung, Taiwan
- 3_{rd} place of "Mahasiswa Berprestasi Vokasi 2018" Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember

2017

1st place of Kontes Robot Indonesia (KRI) 2017
 Humanoid Robot Soccer Competition, Regional
 Level East and Central Java

- 2nd place of KRI 2017 Humanoid Robot Soccer Competition, National level in Bandung, Indonesia
- 2_{nd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2017, Sprint Humanoid Adult Size Robot, Kaoshiung, Taiwan
- 2_{nd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2017, Obstacle Run Humanoid Adult Size Robot, Kaoshiung, Taiwan
- 2_{nd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2017, Mini DRC Humanoid Adult Size Robot, Kaoshiung, Taiwan
- 3_{rd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2017, All Round Humanoid Adult Size Robot, Kaoshiung, Taiwan
- 3_{rd} place of FIRA RoboWorld Cup 2017, Marathon Humanoid Adult Size Robot, Kaoshiung, Taiwan

PORTOFOLIO

Web Personal:

- https://sulaimanali281.github.io/story_my_life/
- https://linktr.ee/sulaimannali

Youtube:

- https:/
- http://www.youtube.com/c/ICHIROITS

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCxaBXt09h
 DDTGb620OBsx7A?view as=subscriber

Publication:

 Muhtadin et al. (2019) Ichiro Robots Winning RoboCup 2018 Humanoid TeenSize Soccer Competitions. In: Holz D., Genter K., Saad M., von Stryk O. (eds) RoboCup 2018: Robot World Cup XXII. RoboCup 2018. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11374. Springer, Cha